Guide to the Westall Family Papers, 1790-1986 (bulk 1880-1986) and undated RL.01369
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Westall Family papers
1790-1986 (bulk 1880-1986) and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Westall family
RL.01369
2617
6 Linear Feet
Prominent family from Asheville, NC. Includes papers of several different members of the family including correspondence, clippings, speeches, and writings of Virginia Westall in her capacity as aide to General R. L. Eichelberger; papers from family's various civic capacities; WWI and WWII correspondence; military records; family photographs and clippings; other personal correspondence including some related to cousin Thomas Wolfe; photographs of Asheville; Westall genealogy; some poetry, a journal, other writings; business papers including those concerning violin making and some from a family member's construction business in Asheville.
2,226 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Westall Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1977, 1978, 1980, 1981, 1983, and 1998.
Biographical Note
The Westall Family was a prominent family from Asheville, NC.
Collection Overview
Includes papers of several different members of the family including correspondence, clippings, speeches, and writings of Virginia Westall in her capacity as aide to General R. L. Eichelberger; papers from family's various civic capacities; WWI and WWII correspondence; military records; family photographs and clippings; other personal correspondence including some related to cousin Thomas Wolfe; photos of Asheville; Westall genealogy; some poetry, a journal, other writings; business papers including those concerning violin making and some from a family member's construction business in Asheville.
Photographs; World War, 1939-1945 -- Correspondence; World War, 1914-1918 -- Correspondence; Generals -- United States; Clippings (information artifacts); Asheville (N.C.); Westall family; Eichelberger, Robert L.; Wiley, Emily Chedester (Emma); Westall, James M.; Wolfe, Thomas, 1900-1938; Taylor, Virginia Westall; Westall, James M., Jr.
- Westall Family Papers, 1790-1986 (bulk 1880-1986) and undated, 788731; 15 boxes and 1 oversize folder
  Scope and Contents note
  Collection includes correspondence from both World Wars and other personal family records. Also includes some oversize items separated from main collection.
  - Correspondence, 1880-1941 Oct., 788755 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1941 Nov.-1943, 788754 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1944-1949, 788753 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1950-1967, 788752 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, 1968-1972, 788751 (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1973-1981 and undated, 788750 (Box 6)
  - Military papers, circa 1940-1970, 788749 (Box 7)
  - Virginia Westall Taylor Papers, 788748 (Box 7)
  - Print materials, 1883-1980, 788747 (Box 8)
  - Print materials, 1970-1986, 788746 (Box 9)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1980-1986, 788745 (Box 9)
  - Volumes, 1910-1970, 788744 (Box 10)
  - Writings, 1990-1970, 788743 (Box 10)
  - Financial papers, 1945-1976, 788742 (Box 11)
  - Legal papers, 1790-1970, 788741 (Box 11)
  - Letterbook, 1884-1902, 788740 (Box 11)
  - Military records, 788739 (Box 11)
  - Genealogy, 788738 (Box 11)
  - Photographs, 788737 (Box 12)
  - Photo albums, circa 1920-1930, 788736 (Box 13)
  - Photo albums, circa 1910-1920, 788735 (Box 14)
  - Photo albums, circa 1910-1920, 788734 (Box 15)
  - 1891 Map of Asheville, North Carolina, 788733 (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous Oversize, 788732 (Oversize-folder 1)